Frances Benjamin Johnston Collection, 1935-1938 P0006
Frances Benjamin Johnston Collection, 1935-1938
University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Library. North Carolina Collection.
Johnston, Frances Benjamin, 1864-1952.; Boone, Samuel Moyle.
P0006
About 2,280 images (3.57 linear feet in 9 boxes and five drawers in map case)
Frances Benjamin Johnston (1864-1952) was a trained artist who turned her talents to photography and became one of the first prominent female photojournalists in the United States. After studying art at the Académie Julian in Paris, France and at the Art Students' League in Washington, DC; Ms. Johnston took up an interest in journalism and began doing illustrations for newspapers in 1885. She eventually turned to photography because she thought it was the more accurate machine and studied under Thomas William Smillie, head of the Division of Photography at the Smithsonian Institution. During her long and successful career Johnston took tens of thousands of photographs of scenes and events all over the United States with an emphasis on Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Alabama, Mississippi, and Louisiana.
The Frances Benjamin Johnston (1864-1952) Collection contains photographs made between 1935 and 1938 of historic structures of architectural interest throughout North Carolina. Many of the photographs in this collection subsequently appeared in The Early Architecture of North Carolina by Frances Benjamin Johnston and Thomas T. Waterman.
Administrative Information
Restrictions to Access
No restrictions. Open for research.
Acquisitions Information
There are three sources for the photographs in this collection:
Accession numbers 1676–2533: In the summer of 1949, Samuel M. Boone of Chapel Hill made photographic prints from Frances Benjamin Johnston's original negatives. The University of North Carolina Library at Chapel Hill arranged with Johnston for Boone to move into her home on Bourbon Street in New Orleans and use her darkroom to print the images.
Accession numbers 2534–2742: A gift of Charles A. and Ruth C. Cannon in 1953, this group of photographs comprise 209 8x10-inch sepia prints made, according to the deed of gift, through the interest and aid of the donors. Materials included in this group have a stamp that reads: Frances Benjamin Johnston, Arts Club of Washington, 2017 Eye Street Northwest, Washington D.C.
Accession numbers 2757–2968: More than 200 oversized prints originally given by John Sprunt Hill to the Southern Historical Collection at the University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill, which transferred them to the North Carolina Collection in 1952.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Johnston, Frances Benjamin, 1864-1952.
Women photographers--United States.
Locations:
Airlie (N.C.)--Photographs.
Arden (N.C.)--Photographs.
Asheville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Aventon (N.C.)--Photographs.
Beaufort County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Bath (N.C.)--Photographs.
Bear Poplar (N.C.)--Photographs.
Beaufort (N.C.)--Photographs.
Beaufort County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Blowing Rock (N.C.)--Photographs.
Brunswick (N.C.)--Photographs.
Brunswick County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Buck Hill (N.C.)--Photographs.
Buncombe County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Burke County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Cabarrus County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Caldwell County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Chapel Hill (N.C.)--Photographs.
Carteret County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Caswell County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Catawba River (N.C.)--Photographs.
Cedar Point (N.C.)--Photographs.
Centerville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Charlotte (N.C.)--Photographs.
China Grove (N.C.)--Photographs.
Chowan County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Cleveland County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Columbus (N.C.)--Photographs.
Concord (N.C.)--Photographs.
Cornelius (N.C.)--Photographs.
Craven County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Crowells (N.C.)--Photographs.
Cumberland County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Currituck County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Dallas (N.C.)--Photographs.
Davidson (N.C.)--Photographs.
Davidson County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Davie County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Denver (N.C.)--Photographs.
Duplin County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Durham (N.C.)--Photographs.
Durham County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Edenton (N.C.)--Photographs.
Edgecombe County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Elizabeth City (N.C.)--Photographs.
Elmwood (N.C.)--Photographs.
Fayetteville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Flat Rock (N.C.)--Photographs.
Fletcher (N.C.)--Photographs.
Fort Bragg (N.C.)--Photographs.
Forsyth County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Franklin County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Gaston County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Gastonia (N.C.)--Photographs.
Gibsonville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Guilford County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Halifax (N.C.)--Photographs.
Halifax County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Hampstead (N.C.)--Photographs.
Happy Valley (N.C.)--Photographs.
Harvey's Neck (N.C.)--Photographs.
Henderson (N.C.)--Photographs.
Henderson County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Hertford (N.C.)--Photographs.
Hertford County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Hickory Nut Gap (N.C.)--Photographs.
High Point (N.C.)--Photographs.
Hillsborough (N.C.)--Photographs.
Hoke County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Huntersville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Inez (N.C.)--Photographs.
Iredell County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Iron Station (N.C.)--Photographs.
Jackson (N.C.)--Photographs.
Jamestown (N.C.)--Photographs.
Kings Mountain (N.C.)--Photographs.
Lake Lure (N.C.)--Photographs.
Lake Phelps (N.C.)--Photographs.
Lincoln County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Lincolnton (N.C.)--Photographs.
Littleton (N.C.)--Photographs.
Louisburg (N.C.)--Photographs.
McDowell County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Marion (N.C.)--Photographs.
Mecklenburg County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Mills Spring (N.C.)--Photographs.
Morganton (N.C.)--Photographs.
Mount Holly (N.C.)--Photographs.
Mount Mourne (N.C.)--Photographs.
Mount Olive (N.C.)--Photographs.
Moyock (N.C.)--Photographs.
Muddy Creek (N.C.)--Photographs.
Murfeesboro (N.C.)--Photographs.
Nash County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Nashville (N.C.)--Photographs.
New Bern (N.C.)--Photographs.
New Hanover County (N.C.)--Photographs.
New Market Township (N.C.)--Photographs.
Nixonton (N.C.)--Photographs.
Northampton County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Old Sparta (N.C.)--Photographs.
Old Town (N.C.)--Photographs.
Orange County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Pasquotank County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Pender County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Perquimans County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Polk County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Raleigh (N.C.)--Photographs.
Randolph County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Rockingham County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Rocky Ford (N.C.)--Photographs.
Rocky Mount (N.C.)--Photographs.
Rowan County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Rugby (N.C.)--Photographs.
Rutherford County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Salisbury (N.C.)--Photographs.
Saluda (N.C.)--Photographs.
South Mills (N.C.)--Photographs.
Sowers Ferry (N.C.)--Photographs.
Spencer (N.C.)--Photographs.
Stagville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Tarboro (N.C.)--Photographs.
Taylors Cross Roads (N.C.)--Photographs.
Townsville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Tryon (N.C.)--Photographs.
Tyrrell County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Valle Crucis (N.C.)--Photographs.
Vance County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Wake County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Warren County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Warrenton (N.C.)--Photographs.
Washington (N.C.)--Photographs.
Watauga County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Wayne County (N.C.)--Photographs.
Westminster (N.C.)--Photographs.
Wells Crossroads (N.C.)--Photographs.
Wentworth (N.C.)--Photographs.
Williamsboro (N.C.)--Photographs.
Wilmington (N.C.)--Photographs.
Winston-Salem (N.C.)--Photographs.
Yanceyville (N.C.)--Photographs.
Related Collections:
North Carolina Collection Photographic Archives: North Carolina County Collection (P1)
Biographical Note
Frances Benjamin Johnston was born 15 January 1864 in Rochester, New York. Her family later moved to Washington, District of Columbia. In 1882, at the age of 18, she attended Notre Dame Convent in Govanston, Maryland. The following year Johnston departed for Paris, France, to study studied art at the Académie Julian. After her return from Paris in 1885, Johnston enrolled in the Art Students' League in Washington.
Johnston's interest in art shifted to journalism, her mother's occupation, and she began to make illustrations for newspapers. She eventually turned to photography because she thought it was the more accurate machine and studied under Thomas William Smillie, head of the Division of Photography at the Smithsonian Institution. Johnston worked on many important projects during her storied career, including the Carnegie Survey of the Architecture of the South between 1933 and 1940. The survey was a systematic record of the early buildings and gardens in Maryland, Virgina, the Carolinas, Georgia, Alabama, Louisiana, Florida, and Mississippi.
Johnston's original negatives for the project are at the Library of Congress, which has become the principal repository of her writings and photographs. The Frances Benjamin Johnston Collection at the Library of Congress includes approximately 20,000 photographs and 3,700 glass and film negatives. Images in the collection span the period 1864-1940, but the majority date between 1897 and 1927. In 1936, the American Council of Learned Societies paid Johnston $3,500 to photograph early North Carolina architecture.
She had three mentors for the project: from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Albert Ray Newsome, North Carolina historian and former history department chair and Howard Odum, sociologist of the American South, professor, and founder of the Sociology Department, the School of Public Welfare, the Department of City and Regional Planning, and the Institute for Research in Social Science; and from Duke University, William Boyd, history professor and first Director of the Libraries.
Frances Benjamin Johnston died in 1952. Source: The Woman Behind the Lens: the Life and Work of Frances Benjamin Johnston, 1864-1952, by Bettina Berch. Charlottesville: University Press of Virginia, 2000.
Collection Overview
This collection contains 1,100 photographs created by Frances Benjamin Johnston (1864-1952) between 1935 and 1938 that document historic structures of architectural interest in forty-eight counties throughout North Carolina. The majority of the images in this collection were created from the original negatives in 1941. Many of the photographs subsequently appeared in The Early Architecture of North Carolina by Frances Benjamin Johnston and Thomas T. Waterman, published by the University of North Carolina Press in 1941.
Johnston was a trained artist who turned her talents to photography and became one of the first prominent female photojournalists in the United States. After studying art at the Académie Julian in Paris, France and at the Art Students' League in Washington, DC, Ms. Johnston took up an interest in journalism and began doing illustrations for newspapers in 1885. She eventually turned to photography because she thought it was the more accurate machine and studied under Thomas William Smillie, head of the Division of Photography at the Smithsonian Institution. During her long and successful career Johnston took tens of thousands of photographs of scenes and events all over the United States with an emphasis on Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Alabama, Mississippi, and Louisiana. The majority of the materials in this collection are stored in record center boxes (boxes 1-9) and oversized items are stored in five map case drawers (boxes 10-14).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Frances Benjamin Johnston Collection, 1935-1938., Items: 2,280 images. Approximately 3.57 Linear Feet. Nine document boxes and five drawers in map case.
  Arrangement: Subject.
  This series contains approximately 2,280 images. A majority of the images are stored in record center boxes (1-9) and oversized items are in five map case drawers (listed as boxes 10-14). The materials in boxes 1-9 came to the North Carolina Collection from either Samuel Boone (accession 1676-2533) or the Cannon family (accession 2534-2742). The oversized materials came to the North Carolina Collection (via the Southern Historical Collection) from John Sprunt Hill (accession 2757-2968).
  - Beaufort County: Bath: Saint Thomas Episcopal Church, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 8 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0001)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2006-2009.
  - Beaufort County: Bath: Saint Thomas Episcopal Church, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0002)
  - Beaufort County: Washington: Bank of Washington, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0003)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2005.
  - Beaufort County: Washington: Beaufort County Courthouse, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0004)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2004.
  - Beaufort County: Washington: Belfont House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0005)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2002.
  - Beaufort County: Washington: Creedmere House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0006)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2001.
  - Brunswick County: Brunswick: Orton Plantation, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0007)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2090-2091.
  - Brunswick County: Brunswick: Orton Plantation, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0008)
  - Brunswick County: Brunswick: Saint Phillips Episcopal Church, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 7 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0009)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2094-2097.
  - Brunswick County: Brunswick: Saint Phillips Episcopal Church, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0010)
  - Buncombe County: Arden: Struan House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 8 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0011)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2029-2031.
  - Buncombe County: Asheville: All Souls Episcopal Church, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0012)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2021.
  - Buncombe County: Asheville: Biltmore Estate, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 14 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0013)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2010-2017.
  - Buncombe County: Hickory Nut Gap: Sherrill Inn, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 34 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0014)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2037-2058; Includes one framed print.
  - Buncombe County: Hickory Nut Gap: Houses, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0015)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2034.
  - Burke County: Bellevue, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0016)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2060.
  - Burke County: Creekside (Thomas Walton House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0017)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2085-2084.
  - Burke County: Creekside (Thomas Walton House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0018)
  - Burke County: Magnolia, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0019)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2063-2065.
  - Burke County: Stoney Hill, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0020)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2082.
  - Burke County: Morganton: Burke County Courthouse, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0021)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2062.
  - Burke County: Morganton: Pleasant Valley (Alfred Perkins House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 14 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0022)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2067-2074.
  - Burke County: Morganton: Quaker Meadows, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 6 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0023)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2076-2078.
  - Burke County: Morganton: Swan Ponds, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0024)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2083.
  - Burke County: Morganton: Willow Hill (Collett Place), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0025)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2088.
  - Burke County: Muddy Creek: Rutherford House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0026)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2079-2081.
  - Cabarrus County: Concord: Doorway of the Mrs: Charles Cannon House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0027)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2099.
  - Cabarrus County: Concord: Governor Nathaniel Alexander's Birthplace, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 4 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0028)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2098.
  - Cabarrus County: Concord: Mill Hill (Jacob Stigerwalt House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 8 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0029)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2101-2105.
  - Cabarrus County: Concord: Mill Hill (Jacob Stigerwalt House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 4 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0030)
  - Caldwell County: Clover Hill: Clover Hill (Colonel Edmund Jones House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 6 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0031)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2107-2109.
  - Caldwell County: Clover Hill: Clover Hill (Colonel Edmund Jones House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0032)
  - Caldwell County: Fireplace Mantle at Fort Defiance (William Lenoir House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0033)
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Carteret County Courthouse, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0034)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2115.
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Duncan Tavern, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0035)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2127.
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Duncan Tavern, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0036)
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Joseph House (Henry House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0037)
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Joseph House (Henry House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0038)
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Houses, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0039)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2123.
  - Carteret County: Beaufort: Houses, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0040)
    1 image.
  - Carteret County: Cedar Point: Octagon House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0041)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2116-2118.
  - Carteret County: Fort Macon Stairways, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 4 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0042)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2119-2121.
  - Carteret County: Fort Macon Stairways, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0043)
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Dongola (Graves House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0044)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2140-2143.
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Dongola (Graves House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0045)
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Forest House (Poteat House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0046)
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Forest House (Poteat House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0047)
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Melrose (John Williams House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 13 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0048)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2144-2149.
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Melrose (John Williams House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0049)
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Rose Hill (Bedford Brown House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 15 images (Printbox 1, Bwpprint P0006/0050)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2134-2138; Includes two framed prints.
  - Caswell County: Yanceyville: Rose Hill (Bedford Brown House), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0051)
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Athol (Joshua Skinner Home), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 4 images (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0052)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2151.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Athol (Joshua Skinner Home), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0053)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2151.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Beverly Hall (Early eighteenth century house), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 3 images (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0054)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2153.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Bockover, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 2 images (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0055)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2154-2155.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Booth House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0056)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2184.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Booth House (built circa 1767), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0057)
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Chowan County Courthouse, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 13 images (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0058)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2156-2160.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Chowan County Courthouse (built circa 1767), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 5 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0059)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2157, NC2158, NC2878.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Chowan County Jail, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 1 image (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0060)
    Original (Johnston) negative number: NC2161.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Cupola House, circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 22 images (Printbox 2, Bwpprint P0006/0061)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2207-2228; Includes one framed print.
  - Chowan County: Edenton: Cupola House (built circa 1715), circa 1935-1938, Black-and-White Photographic Prints; 8 images (Flatfile 1, Oimage P0006/0062)
    Original (Johnston) negative numbers: NC2212, NC2213, NC2217, NC2218.